<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flick on #!/slash/note</title>
    <link>https://leonjza.github.io/categories/flick/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flick on #!/slash/note</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 06:36:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://leonjza.github.io/categories/flick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>flick II vuln vm with a mobile twist</title>
      <link>https://leonjza.github.io/blog/2015/08/21/flick-ii-vuln-vm-with-a-mobile-twist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 06:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonjza.github.io/blog/2015/08/21/flick-ii-vuln-vm-with-a-mobile-twist/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://leonjza.github.io/images/flickII_logo.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;tl;dr&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flick II just got published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vulnhub.com/entry/flick-2,122/&#34;&gt;Vulnhub&lt;/a&gt;! You should try it =)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about a year since &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vulnhub.com/entry/flick-1,99/&#34;&gt;Flick I&lt;/a&gt;, I have finally managed to get Flick II out to VulnHub. I learned a lot from Flick I and as a result applied it to Flick II. The making of Flick II was also a very different story. If I have to compare it to the first one (which took 3 nights to build start to finish), Flick II took &lt;em&gt;waay&lt;/em&gt; longer. I think the total build / testing time must be over a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally I had a whole bunch of ideas, and after lots of trial and error, came to what it has become today. I have to give a special shouts to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/s4gi_&#34;&gt;@s4gi_&lt;/a&gt; for the inspiration to go with the mobile app idea and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/barrebas&#34;&gt;@barrebas&lt;/a&gt; for testing the first &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; broken version :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparation&#34;&gt;preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe Flick II will be the first Vulnerable VM on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/VulnHub&#34;&gt;@VulnHub&lt;/a&gt; with a mobile twist to it. That means you will need to either install the bundled &lt;code&gt;.apk&lt;/code&gt; on an Android phone, or run it in an Android emulator in order to progress on the path to root! The &lt;code&gt;.apk&lt;/code&gt; is self-signed so expect Android to complain about that if you install it on a phone. Don&amp;rsquo;t feel bad if you don’t trust me (aka. some random guy on the internet). If you don’t, your safest bet then is to use an emulator. The only real requirement for the &lt;code&gt;.apk&lt;/code&gt; is that the mobile app must be able to speak to the VM and be run on a relatively recent Android version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you get to learn as much as I did making it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck! :D&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>flick can you find the flag?</title>
      <link>https://leonjza.github.io/blog/2014/08/07/flick-can-you-find-the-flag/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 12:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonjza.github.io/blog/2014/08/07/flick-can-you-find-the-flag/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://leonjza.github.io/images/flick_logo.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a CTF! You should try it! Find it &lt;a href=&#34;http://vulnhub.com/entry/flick-1,99/&#34;&gt;on Vulnhub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreword&#34;&gt;foreword&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, security CTF&amp;rsquo;s are fun. A lot of fun. And can be one heck of a time sink! Checking my laptops time and realizing its 3am on a week night is normal when I get pulled into one. The frustration, the trolls, the tremendous amounts of learning is all part of the experience of a successful CTF in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparation&#34;&gt;preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having done a few now with varying degrees of success has inspired me to attempt to do the same. So, off I went to CTF island and came back a weekend later with &amp;ldquo;Flick&amp;rdquo;. There is no real meaning to &amp;ldquo;Flick&amp;rdquo;. In fact, the name is the result of: &amp;ldquo;What can I call it?&amp;rdquo; &amp;lt; insert 5u seconds &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Flick?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Flick&amp;rdquo; aims to give you chance to learn something new. While some things may be trivial for the seasoned penetration tester by day, there may also be one or two things to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as hints go, there is not much to give in the beginning. You have to &lt;em&gt;find&lt;/em&gt; the flag.txt. It is possible to read it without having root command execution, however, as a added challenge, can you get root command execution? :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing your experiences with it and good luck! You can find me in #vulnhub on freenode or on twitter @leonjza&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>