<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jabber on #!/bin/note
</title>
    <link>https://leonjza.github.io/categories/jabber/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jabber on #!/bin/note
</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/leonjza&#34;&gt;@leonjza&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leonjza.github.io/categories/jabber/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jabber to Email using SleekXMPP</title>
      <link>https://leonjza.github.io/blog/2013/06/07/jabber-to-email-using-sleekxmpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonjza.github.io/blog/2013/06/07/jabber-to-email-using-sleekxmpp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-why-would-you-even-want-this&#34;&gt;So, why would you even want this..?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, to be honest, I am not really sure of many use cases for this, however maybe someone, somewhere will need to do something like this, and I would have done my deed and saved someone some time :☀:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introducing-sleekxmpp&#34;&gt;Introducing SleekXMPP&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sleekxmpp.com/&#34;&gt;SleekXMPP&lt;/a&gt; is a python XMPP framework. It takes a bit to get your head around it, but once you have some basics covered its quite a rewarding library to work with. :) To start, you need to install 2 dependencies. Python Mailer and SleekXMPP itself. Something like &lt;code&gt;pip install mailer sleekxmpp&lt;/code&gt; or for the older school, &lt;code&gt;easy_install sleekxmpp mailer&lt;/code&gt; should do the trick. It can&amp;rsquo;t hurt to check if the distro you use has these are packages already too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To: Extremely simple python Jabber Broadcast Bot</title>
      <link>https://leonjza.github.io/blog/2013/05/25/how-to-extremely-simple-python-jabber-broadcast-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leonjza.github.io/blog/2013/05/25/how-to-extremely-simple-python-jabber-broadcast-bot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;bots-bots-bots&#34;&gt;Bots! Bots! Bots!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, a &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;bot&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; is something that like &lt;em&gt;does work for you&lt;/em&gt;. But, for this purpose, the need for a jabber bot came from the fact that I had to deal with a lot of email on a daily basis. This large amount of mail sometimes would cause me to completely miss critical mail alerts. Realising later that I could have prevented a catastrophe if I didn&amp;rsquo;t miss that &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; email was just not on anymore. So, I started investigating ways to get the &lt;em&gt;important&lt;/em&gt; stuff delivered faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a team at work, we have long gone dropped the whole Skype group chat thing for our own Jabber server. My privacy related concerns back then was recently heightened &lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.randombit.net/pipermail/cryptography/2013-May/004224.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; when a trap URL received a HEAD request from &lt;strong&gt;65.52.100.214&lt;/strong&gt;. The user that received the URL in a chat was under strict instructions not to actually click it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
